第一幕
翻译：灰灰是菇凉
翻译：小酸奶
德语：Margaery liulifox
校对：小酸奶
后期：吉吉
帕特里夏
Patricia.
我有个病人五分钟后到
So, I have a patient that is coming in five minutes.
我可以让他一会儿再过来
I can ask him to come back later.
请进
Please.
我脑子里一直萦绕着一首歌  声音很响
This song, it's stuck in my head, and it's so loud.
正在诊疗
您明白我的意思吗
Do you see what I mean?
他们还是会保住她的命
They're going to try to keep her alive after all.
马科斯
Markos?
快  赶在那帮小伙子抢走座位之前占住座位
Quick! Get the seats over there before the boys take them.
那个吉他手真帅
The guitarist is so cute.
我是对的
I was right.
她们是女巫
They are witches.
我得让莎拉快跑
I have to tell Sara to get out of there.
我只关心她
She's the only girl I actually give a damn about.
她的幻觉加深了恐惧
她坚定不移地相信自己构建的神话
要是我扔下她跑了
If I leave without her,
她们下次也许就会选她
they may pick her next.
或者奥尔加
Or Olga.
我还得警告奥尔加
I should warn Olga, too.
奥尔加已经有所察觉
Olga's already figured out things.
她看到她们是怎么诱骗我的了
She saw how they groomed me.
那栋楼里还有很多你们看不见的东西
There's more in that building than what you can see.
战争结束后他们就一直暗中活动
They've been underground since the war.
你觉得他们现在能监听你吗
And you think they can hear you now?
一开始  她们对我很好
At the beginning, they gave me things.
我生活很有条理  能好好睡觉
Perfect balance, perfect sleep.
他们跟我们用心交流
Talking with our minds.
但后来她们剪去了我的头发
But they took my hair.
拿走了我的尿  他们...
They took my urine. They...
她们拿走了我的眼睛
They took my eyes.
现在她能看见我了
Now she can see me.
《死亡心理学》
马科斯母亲
Mother Markos.
她想要控制我的思想
Oh, she wants to get inside of me.
我能感觉到她
I can feel her.
我那时还以为是我自己想这样
Oh, I thought I wanted it.
幻像
我让事情变成这样
I let it happen.
你明白我的意思吗
Do you understand me?
要是他们知道我来过这儿  绝不会有一丝犹豫
If they find out I was here, they won't hesitate.
他们会杀了我  把我的阴部装在盘子里吃掉
They'll hollow me out and eat my cunt on a plate.
贝尔格先生在等您  医生
Mr. Berger is waiting for you, Doctor.
-贝尔格先生  -医生
- Mr. Berger.  - Mr. Doctor.
请进
Please.
母亲能取代任何无可取代的位置
很好  很好
Okay, that's good. That's good.
早上好  牧师
Morning, Pastor.
你们的衣服都淋湿了吗
Did the rain get your clothes all wet?
没有  别担心  姑娘们都把衣服晾起来了
No, don't you worry. The girls just hung that all up.
收音机上说
Two days of rain
雨要下两天
is what I just heard on the radio.
-这样差不多就行了  -差不多
- That'll just about do it. - Just about.
她今天怎么样
How is she today?
跟之前一样
Much the same.
叹息站
出口
您是坦纳小姐吗
You're Miss Tanner?
-是的  -进来吧
- Yes. - Come in.
我今早打电话去你住的酒店
I tried to call you at your hotel this morning
想问你是否能改约
to ask you if you could reschedule.
-为什么  -舞团有事
- Why? - Company business.
今天不太好接待你
It's not a good time just today.
不过你已经来了
But here you are.
马科斯舞团
1969年4月15日
星期五
一  二
And one, and two,
三  四
and three, and four,
五
and five,
六  七
and six, and seven,
八
and eight.
提肘  一
Elbows up. And one...
进来吧  苏西
Come in, Susie.
米利乌斯和曼德尔小姐是舞团的声乐教师
Miss Millius and Miss Mandel are the company's repetiteurs.
维瓦·布兰克呢
And Veva Blanc?
我听说她会来
I was told she would be here.
亲爱的
Oh, dear.
你没有参加过正式训练  也没有介绍信
You have no formal training or references.
你一直坚持参加面试
Your insistence to audition
正好碰上那天布兰克夫人心情好
happened to catch Madame Blanc on a good day.
但你的资质真的不适合这里
But you really shouldn't be here at all.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
明白了吗
Yeah?
很好
Good.
那就开始吧
Then let's begin.
我跳舞还是喜欢不加伴奏
I prefer dancing without music.
谢谢
Danke schoen.
你可以在脑子里数节奏  对吗
You can keep time in your head, yes?
入睡
Hypnose.
来
And here we have...
肘部成一条线
a line between the elbows.
面朝前
Face forward.
很好  睡着
Perfect, and... Morphus.
注意手不要太贴近脸
And here, not so close to the face.
要像手里捧着一只小鸟的感觉
More like you're holding a bird or something.
我们早上排练的时候他们弄好的
They did it when we were in morning rehearsal.
他们把她的东西打包邮寄了
They just put her things in shipping boxes.
你不会觉得她以后都不能露面了吧
You don't think she had to go underground, do you?
我不在乎发生了什么事
I don't care what happened.
我只想她打个电话过来
I just want her to call.
我很担心她
I'm really worried.
班尼恩小姐
Fraulein Bannion.
来吧
Kommen Sie.
我刚和布兰克夫人谈过了
I've just spoken with Madame Blanc.
你做得很好  班尼恩小姐
Well done, Miss Bannion.
我想你得回家去
I imagine you will need to return home
准备下东西  打点好事情
to settle things and make arrangements
搬来柏林了
for moving to Berlin.
不  不用
No. No, no.
我现在就可以开始
I can start right now.
很好
Good.
这位是布歇小姐
This is Miss Boutaher,
我们的技术总监
our technical director.
你好
Guten Tag.
这位是凡德加斯小姐
And this is Miss Vendegast.
-她是这里  -你好
- She acts as house mother... - Hello.
住家舞者的女舍监
...for our dancers who reside here.
你从哪里过来的
Where'd you come from?
俄亥俄州
Ohio.
我们这边就像是露丝·布雷笔下的妇女合作社
We operate as a sort of Ruth Bré collective.
伊丽莎白·博恩斯的笔名  德国剧作家  父权制批判者
因为我们给舞者的工资不多
As we cannot pay our dancers a lot of money,
我们提供宿舍  费用全免
we offer dormitory-style rooms, rent-free.
你们  你们完全不收费吗
You don't... you don't charge anything at all?
不收一分钱
Not a mark.
我们舞团完全理解
In this company, we fully understand
女性财务自主权的重要性
the importance of a woman's financial autonomy.
往常到每年的这个时候  宿舍都住满了
Normally, it would be full at this time of year,
不过我们正好空出来了一间
but we have had a room open.
嗯  帕特里夏那间
Yeah. Patricia's.
你认识帕特里夏吗
Do you know Patricia?
不  我听到走廊里
No, I heard some girls talking
有几个女孩在说她的事
about her in the hall.
现在你是我们的一员了  我对你也就不保留了
Now that you're one of us, I won't be coy.
帕特里夏的状态很不好
Patricia has just left the company
离开了舞团
under sad circumstances.
我们觉得她不会回来了
We think she won't be back,
所以你愿意的话房间就是你的了
so there's room if you want.
我们会派一个女孩帮你收拾行李
We'll send you one of our girls to help you with your luggage.
先吃完午饭
After lunch.
你觉得可以吧
It's all right for you?
可以
Yes.
这...这真是
It's-it... it's all...
很好
Yes.
太好了
It's perfect.
你好  你好  抱歉我来晚了
Hello. Hi. I'm sorry I'm late.
-你好  -被雨耽搁了
- Hi. - It's the rain.
每次一下雨  柏林的所有人就都像傻子一样
Whenever it rains in Berlin, everyone jumps in a cab,
跳进出租车里  我们就不坐了吧
and like an idiot, I just let ours go.
你好  我是莎拉
Hi. I'm Sara.
我们去街上碰碰运气
We're gonna have to take our chances on the street.
你有伞吗
Do you have an umbrella?
你六点还没到
Oh, when you weren't here by 6:00,
我就又续住了一晚
I had to take the room for another night.
天哪  苏西  对不起
Oh. God, Susie, I'm sorry.
今天舞团里乱套了
Everything was a mess at the company today.
你在笑什么
Why are you smiling?
对不...我...我
I'm sor... I-I...
你刚刚说柏林
Um, uh, when you said Berlin a second ago,
你说"柏林的所有人"
you said "Everyone in Berlin,"
我就想到  现在我也是这"所有人"之一了
and I just thought that... that includes me now.
我住在柏林了
I live in Berlin.
是的  恭喜你
Yes. Congrats.
我听说你今天可是耀眼的明星
I heard you were a sensation today.
你打电话告诉你家人了吗
Have you called your family yet, to tell them?
布兰克小姐中途看了我的面试
Miss Blanc came into my audition.
但她后来走了
But she left right after.
她很了不起
She's incredible.
她诠释她的作品和传递能量的方式很了不起
The way she transmits her work, her energy.
当你接触到这种能量  会感觉它...
When it shines on you, it's...
令人上瘾
"Addictive" is the word for it.
她很坚强
She's tough.
在战争期间也维持住了舞团
She kept the company alive through the war.
当德意志帝国想要封闭女人的思想
When the Reich just wanted women to shut off their minds
把女人当做生育机器的时候
and keep their uteruses open,
还有布兰克在
there was Blanc.
谢谢
Thank you.
她可是真家伙
La vraie chose.
什么
What?
你说的是法语吗
W-Was that French?
是炸弹爆炸了
It's a bomb.
我可以闻到火药味
I can smell it.
那边有个银行
There's a bank that way.
你不知道发生了什么吗
Don't you know what's happening here?
劫持者正在跟他们谈判
The hijackers are negotiating a release
要求今晚释放施塔姆海姆的囚犯
of the Stammheim prisoners tonight.
是RAF组织
The RAF.
巴德尔-迈因霍夫团伙
Baader-Meinhof.
德国恐怖组织巴德尔和迈因霍夫集团
他们劫持了一个主管
They kidnapped an executive.
战争期间  他是纳粹党卫队军官
During the war, he was a Nazi SS, an officer.
现在他是德国雇主协会主管
Now he runs the German Employers' Association.
你不知道那有多可怕吧
You don't get how awful that is, do you?
抱歉
Sorry.
我只是很担心我的朋友
I'm just worried about my friend.
第二幕
眼泪宫殿
关于这次投票
Now for the voting,
每个人说出自己所选的人名
each of us says the name of her choice.
-曼德尔  你选谁  -马科斯
-Mandel, whom are you voting for? - Markos.
-凯伦  -布兰克
- Kellen? - Blanc.
-尤迪丝  -马科斯
- Judith? - Markos.
-布塔  -布兰克
- Boutaher? - Blanc.
-米流丝  -马科斯
- Millius? - Markos.
-马丁奇  -马科斯
- Martincin? - Markos.
-胡乐  -马科斯
- Huller. - Markos.
-毛切利  -布兰克
- Mauceri? - Blanc.
-马克斯  -马科斯
- Marks? - Markos.
-帕夫拉  -马科斯
- Pavla? - Markos.
-卡布里特  -布兰克
- Kaplitt? - Blanc.
-文德加斯特  -布兰克
- Vendegast? - Blanc.
-巴尔福  -布兰克
- Balfour? - Blanc.
-切瑟斯  -布兰克
- Creusot? - Blanc.
-阿尔贝塔  -马科斯
- Alberta?  - Marcos.
-格非特  格非特  -我们在最后
- Griffith? Griffith? - We are at the end.
你必须选
You must choose.
马科斯母亲
Mother Markos.
布兰克  你选谁
Blanc, whom are you voting for?
我弃权
I abstain.
我选马科斯
I vote for Markos.
马科斯以三票优势胜出
Markos wins by three.
就这么定了
It is decided.
马科斯母亲继续履职
Mother Markos will remain in control.
不许任何人挑战她的权威
Let no ones's vote be held against her.
少数服从多数
And let the will of the majority proceed.
马科斯万岁
Long life to Markos.
劫匪是否会驾驶汉莎航空航班
there is no information yet on whether the hijackers
飞行至第四个地点
will pilot the Lufthansa flight to a fourth destination
以及机上的91名人质的情况尚不明确
or what is the condition of the 91 hostages still presumed aboard.
昨日  其中一名巴勒斯坦劫匪
Yesterday, one of the Palestinian hijackers
正式提出了包括释放所有
issued official demands including the release
关押在施达姆斯坦监狱的RAF成员的要求
of all RAF members incarcerated at Stammshein prison...
母亲找你
Mother asked for you.
昨晚的事过后
She has to know that we can move ahead
她想确定我们还能继续吗
now that last night's business is behind us.
你们都知道我对帕特里夏的担忧
You all knew my concerns about Patricia.
发生在帕特里夏身上的事是很可怕
What happened to Patricia was ghostly.
既然我们已经投过票了  母亲想再试试
But now that we voted Mother wants to try again.
而且要快
And so soon.
问题不仅在于我们要用谁进行下一次尝试
The question isn't just who to try next.
更重要的是不论用哪个女孩
We have to make sure the ritual will work
这次都一定要成功
with whichever girl we choose.
母亲相信你一定已经有主意了
Mother trusts you already have ideas on this subject.
也许莎拉是个好选择
Maybe Sara could be a good option.
是的  派她去接那个美国女孩就对了
Yes. It was right to send her to collect the American girl.
萨拉是舞团的非常好的代表
Sara is a good ambassador for the good company.
她把这当成了家  不是吗
She's made a home here, hasn't she?
她在这感觉很好
She feels good here.
有爱
Loved.
约瑟夫大叔
Uncle Josef!
早上好  亲爱的
Good morning my dear!
-你要去乡间别墅吗  -是的
- Are you going to your country house? - Yes!
冻死我了  我要和克拉拉一起上大学了
I'm freezing my ass off. I'll go to the university later on with Clara.
谁说的
Who is speaking?
-拉康  -拉康
- Lacan. - Ah, Lacan!
克伦佩雷尔医生早上好
Good morning, Doctor Klempere!
去乡间别墅吗
Are you going to the country house?
下一站弗里德里希大街
"Next stop Friedrichstrasse.
本车终点站到了
This train terminates here.
请拿好您的证件准备进入东柏林
Please have your identification ready to enter East Berlin."
安科  看  到处都又落满了树叶
Anke, look... everything is full of leaves again!
我上周四才刚将它们清扫掉
I swept them away just last Tuesday.
卧室在二楼
Bedrooms are on the second floor.
为什么你就不能装出爱我的样子跟我讲话
Why don't you try speaking to me like you love me?
跟平时不一样一回
For a change.
这是我的房间
This is my room.
这边这间
And here...
是你的房间
is yours.
我们是邻居
We're neighbors.
你有需要就敲敲墙壁
You can knock on the wall if you ever need anything.
西萨姆夫人
Frau Sesame?
医生  我在迈尔小姐那拿到了粗粒麦粉
Doctor, I got the semolina from Mrs. Meir.
他们又在放无罪释放红军旅恐怖分子的新闻
They are demonstrating again for the release of the RAF terrorists.
艾思林  曼霍夫
Ensslin, Meinhof...
在战争前  德国有最坚强的女性
Before the war Germany had the strongest women...
就像您的妻子安科
Like your wife Anke.
难道不是吗  医生
Wasn't she strong, Doctor?
艾莉丝广播站上午试播
"First rehearsal in the Iris Studio today.
二十分钟倒计时
In twenty minutes.
你就能全身心放松
You're to lead your own stretches today."
早上好
Good morning.
-早上好  -你好
- Good morning. - Hello.
-早上好  -早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
-你好  -早上好  早上好
- Hi. - Good morning. Good morning.
你的膝盖怎么样了  还好吗
How's your knee? Okay?
你能来太好了
It's wonderful you're here.
谢谢
Thank you.
今天舞团里有件高兴的事
We have some happier company business today.
来了一个新舞者
We have a new dancer.
这位是苏西·班尼恩  她从美国过来加入我们
This is Susie Bannion, who's joining us from America.
我昨天有幸看到了她的面试表现
I was privileged to witness her audition yesterday.
我们很幸运能有她的加入
We are very lucky to have her.
你想说点什么吗  苏西
Would you like to say something, Susie?
我不知道
I don't know.
大家好
Hello.
我还没有融入的感觉
I feel like I'm not even here yet.
我不知道
I don't know.
等你准备好了再加入也不迟
You join in whenever you feel ready,
不着急
but there's no rush.
欢迎来到我们的小家庭
Welcome to our little family.
我叫苏西
I'm Susie.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
好了  今天的排练
All right, so for today's rehearsal,
我想从上次我们学习"人"开始讲
I want to pick up exactly where we left off with Volk.
我和奥尔加谈了
I've spoken to Olga,
她来跳帕特里夏的部分
and she's going to dance Patricia's part.
莎拉  你来跳奥尔加的部分
And, Sara, I'd like you to dance Olga's part.
大家都同意吗
Is everyone happy with that?
好的
Okay.
很好
Good.
不  不不不  不行  请把音乐关掉
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Music off, please.
停一下
One moment.
好了  看着我
Okay, so...
一  二  三
And one, and two, and three.
你得从地上拔起来
You pull it from the ground.
好吗  要记住  有重力
All right? Gravity, remember.
这一面的所有人
And everybody from here, please.
还有坦纳
And Tanner.
一  二  三
One and two and three.
And one, and two, and three.
一  二  三
Und eins, und zwei, und drei.
这是什么狗屎东西
This is shit.
-什么狗屎东西  -好了
- Such shit. - Okay.
我们休息十分钟
Why don't we all break for ten minutes.
你甚至懒得尊重自己的谎言
You can't even be bothered to respect your own lies.
伊万诺娃小姐
Miss Ivanova!
不   没事  没关系
No, no, no, no, no, it's okay.
我们来直面问题
Let's face this.
帕特里夏走了  奥尔加
Patricia is gone, Olga.
我们不知道她去了哪里
We don't know where.
要是她想躲起来  她就不会告诉我们
If she's gone into hiding, she wouldn't have told us,
-对吗  -她本来要告诉别人的
- would she? - She would have told someone.
我们知道她和那些
We know that she had dealings
寻找目标的人做交易
with people who are interested in targets.
我们也知道昨晚在克罗伊茨贝格
And we know there was another bomb
又有炸弹爆炸了
in Kreuzberg last night.
她不会这么做的
She wouldn't do that.
她想实践自己的信仰
She wanted to live her beliefs.
谁不欣赏她这一点呢
Who doesn't admire that?
世界上有太多需要改变的事
And there's so much to change in the world.
如果她想住在
If she wants to live in a cellar
一个装满汽油瓶子的地窖里  那是她的选择
filling bottles with petrol, that's her choice.
如果她被警察枪杀了  大家都会伤心的
And who won't be heartbroken if she's shot by police?
你操控了一切
You manipulate everything.
她不相信你们  因为你是个伪君子
She didn't trust you because you're hypocrites.
你带奥尔加回房间吧  坦纳
Will you take Olga to her room, please, Tanner?
不  坦纳小姐
No, Miss Tanner!
给我叫一辆出租车
Call Olga a cab.
我受够了
She's had enough.
我要打包东西
And is going to pack her things
离开这见鬼的疯人院
and get the fuck out from this box of rabies!
你们这帮女巫
Witches!
抱歉让你看到这些
I'm sorry about that.
这种事很难处理
It's a hot thing we do.
好了  那么谁来跳主角
Okay, so... who will dance the protagonist?
索尼娅
Sonia?
我不行  我做不到
I can't. Not yet.
卡洛琳
Caroline?
很好  我们会想出办法的
Very well. We'll manage.
我建议我们从头开始
I suggest that we all take it from the top.
我来跳
I'll dance.
我了解这支舞
I know it.
纪录片里有
It's in the documentary.
我在图书馆看了无数遍
I-I've seen it a hundred times at the library.
亲爱的  我们演出这支舞前
Sweetheart, we rehearsed this piece
排演了十个月
for ten months before we performed it.
我也去亲眼看过
I've seen it in person, too.
那么你一个人先跳一遍
First do it alone, then.
我们不能拖累其他人
We don't want to put the others at risk.
我们可不想到时候
The last thing we need
有人不小心被踢翻了
is someone to get kicked in the ribs.
好吗
All right?
Marks老师  请放一下音乐
Frau Marks, music please.
好  停停停
Okay, stop. Stop, stop.
停一下
Stop.
好了
All right.
放空你的大脑
Clear your head.
我要你从头来一遍
I want you to start over.
你拉伸了吗
Have you stretched?
这不是在开玩笑
This is no joke.
奥尔加  没事吧
Olga. Everything alright?
奥尔加
Olga.
过来
Come here.
来
Come.
到我这来
Come to me.
记住  音乐一播放你就开始
Remember, you start on one with the music,
什么时候感觉不好了  就停下
and if you feel ill at any time, just stop.
从这个动作开始
You start here.
音乐
And...
音乐调大
Lauter!
很好  好极了  苏西
Bravo. Bravo, Susie.
会好的
It'll pass.
你不是第一个感到头晕的
You're not the first dancer who lost the room.
我一般不会头晕
I'm not usually dizzy.
偶尔的崩溃
An occasional collapse
可能都能算是职业病了吧
is a vocational hazard, I'm afraid.
我  我没有  我没有崩溃
I-I didn't... I didn't collapse.
你跪在了地板上  舞蹈的结束动作不是这个
You're on the floor, and that's not where the dance ends.
我只是不想吐在你的练习室里
I was trying not to throw up in your studio.
苏西  没关系的
Susie, it's fine.
你表现得很好
It was wonderful.
莎拉  请你带她回房间吧
Sara, can you take her to her room, please?
你今天就休息吧
You can rest for the rest of the day.
-很不错的开始  -好了  姑娘们
- How enlightening. - Okay, come on, girls.
我们开始
Let's go.
一  二  三
And one, and two, and three.
还有
And...
德国
柏林
不  苏西
No, Susie.
我们必须学习美国
We have to study America.
我说了不行
I said no.
苏珊娜
Susanna.
没事吧
Everything fine?
黑暗之母
眼泪之母
叹息之母
马科斯母亲
请注意
Attention, please!
不要伤害奥尔加
Don't hurt Olga.
慢慢地
Slowly...
布兰克夫人
抬出去
Out!
警察局  你好
Police station, good evening.
你好  我要报警  一个年轻女孩失踪了
Good evening, I'm reporting a young woman who may be missing.
她不可能知道自己在做什么
She couldn't have known what she was doing.
她只不过比我们预想得更合适
She just carried more of our intention than we expected.
我们还迁怒于奥尔加
We also let ourselves get angry with Olga.
不  不是时候
No. I'm not saying that yet.
我能感受到  但是这个女孩很自然
I could feel it. But the girl is natural.
就像帕特里夏  只是更干净些
Like Patricia. Only clean somehow.
她可能比我们想要的更出色
She may be more what we're looking for.
甚至超过萨拉
Even than Sara.
我们是要那么做吗
Are we saying that?
你看起来还是不太好
You don't look better.
你一直都这么苍白吗
Or are you this pale all the time?
你自己好好休息吧
I will leave you.
晚安
Good night.
十七世纪
The Amish split
阿米什人从门诺教派中分裂出来
from the Mennonites in the 17th century.
他们担心门诺教派
They were worried the Mennonites
变得过于自由了
were becoming too liberal.
"他们"  不是"我们"
"They"? Not "We"?
你把宗教思想抛在脑后了
You've left religious thinking behind you, then?
你不喜欢谈论这些事情
And you're not comfortable talking about these things.
我不知道为什么要谈
I don't know why we are.
你真是一个让人感到好奇的人
It's difficult not to be curious about you.
短短两天之内  你参加了面试
In two days, you've auditioned,
被录取了  又成了主舞
been accepted and danced a lead.
你是什么时候开始决定要加入我们的
How did your journey towards us begin?
我之前去了纽约
I went to New York.
去了玛莎·格雷厄姆中心
To the Martha Graham Center.
我看了三次你们的演出
I saw you there three times.
第一次是坐巴士去的
I went once by bus,
之后两次是搭车去的
then I hitchhiked the other two.
那很危险
That's risky.
你被惩罚了吗
Were you punished?
是的
Yeah.
但我当时感觉我必须去看你们
But I felt I had to see you.
今天在《人》的创作者面前
What did it feel today
跳了这支舞  你感觉如何
to dance Volkin front of the one who made it?
不  不对  这个问题太浅薄了
No, no. That's a vain question.
我问你另一个问题
Let me ask you another.
你在跳舞的时候  你内心
When you were dancing, what did it feel like...
你体内是什么感觉
inside you, inside your body?
感觉就像我想象中的做爱的感觉
It felt like what I think it must feel like to fuck.
你是说跟男人做爱吗
You mean to fuck a man?
不  我
No, I...
我想的是类似于动物交配
was thinking of an animal.
你当时看起来
You looked...
我让卡洛琳帮助你练习跳跃
I'm going to ask Caroline to work on your jumps with you.
你跳的还远远不够好
Yours are nowhere near good enough yet.
我们得把你培养好
We'll have to build you up.
这样你们演出这支舞的时候
So that I can dance the protagonist
我可以跳主角吗
when you perform it?
那我就得看到你一次次跳出这种水平
I'll need to see you dance at this level time and time again.
我可以
I can do it.
奥尔加跳起来就像是个举重运动员
Olga made Volk seem like such heavy lifting.
她从来都不理解《人》的核心
She never understood the heart of Volk.
她缺乏信念
She lacked conviction.
还好她走了
I'm relieved she's gone.
这还多亏你的帮忙
Thank you for your help with that.
布兰克夫人
Madame Blanc...
想让我在《人》里跳主舞
wants me to dance the protagonist in Volk.
我没想到会这样
I didn't think it was gonna be like this.
她人很好
She's so kind.
真好
That's wonderful.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  我只是...
I'm fine. I was just...
我在想排练时奥尔加说的话
I was just thinking about what Olga said in rehearsal.
关于帕特里夏的事
About Patricia.
什么意思
What do you mean?
她参加了政治团体
She was active in some political groups.
没人知道她到底在哪里
No one knows where she is, really.
她还好吗
If she's all right.
那是真的吗
Was it true...
奥尔加说的
what Olga said?
是的
Yes.
帕特里夏不相信那些女管理员
Patricia didn't trust the matrons.
我从来都不知道原因
And I never understood why.
要是我明天求你帮个忙  你会帮我吗
If I asked you for a favor tomorrow, would you do it?
会
Yes.
我们可能会被抓到的
We might get caught.
好的
Okay.
母亲  母亲
Mother. Mother.
母亲
Mother.
母亲  母亲  母亲  母亲
Mother. Mother. Mother. Mother.
母亲  母亲
Mother. Mother.
苏珊娜
Susanna.
谁
Who?
女巫
Witches!
第三幕
借
请进  快
Come inside, hurry up!
有何贵干
What do you want?
我们想找负责人谈谈
We need to talk to someone in charge.
马科斯老师
Miss Markos!
事关一个年轻女孩  她叫帕特里夏
About a girl named Patrizia...
帕特里夏·辛格
Patricia Hingle.
有叫布兰克的吗
Someone named Blanc then?
我就是
I'm she.
进来说吧  请  跟我来
Why don't you come in? Please... follow me.
-早上好  -早上好
- Guten Morgen. - Guten Morgen.
早上好
Morgen.
Guten Morgen.
我知道  太疯狂了
Yeah, I know. It's crazy.
好了  我们下回见
Okay, well, let's meet soon.
不  我  我准备好了
Yeah, no, I'm-I'm... I'm ready.
我快出门了
I'm almost out the door.
好  好的
Okay. Yeah.
-回头见  -马尔凯塔
- I'll see you soon. - Marketa.
-马尔凯塔  过来  -回见
- Marketa, come on. - I'll see you soon.
快过来
Come on.
过来  来  快来
Come, come, come.
你确定没人会来吗
Are you sure no one's coming?
确定  别担心
Oh, I'm sure. Don't worry.
周末没人会来这里的
Nobody comes here during the weekend.
这里没有帕特里夏的
Patricia's isn't here.
找找奥尔加的
Try looking for Olga's.
奥尔加
Olga...
她的也没有
She's not here.
我需要号码
I just need a number.
要能打给她父母或是谁  能确切告诉我
For her parents or someone who can tell me for sure
她在不在柏林
she is or isn't in Berlin.
好奇怪
Hmm. How odd.
1961年
1955年
1949年
真古怪
It's bizarre.
什么都没有
There's nothing.
快走吧
Come on.
坐下
Sit down.
今天早上
This morning,
我们把自己的本能转向内心
we turn our instincts inward.
米利乌斯小姐  曼德尔小姐
Miss Millius, Miss Mandel,
请把镜子盖上  好吗
can you close the mirrors, please?
马科斯小姐  不放音乐
Miss Marks, no music.
我想开始一段新的作品
I want to start work on a new piece.
关于重生
A piece about rebirths.
它们施加的不可避免的拉扯
The inevitable pull that they exert
以及我们努力的逃离
and our efforts to escape them.
我们现在开始学习  但是  苏西
We'll learn it now, but, Susie,
你可以随心即兴发挥
you will improvise freely at its heart.
我对你的本能很感兴趣
I'm interested in your instincts here.
这个作品将被命名为"Weider Öffnen"
The piece will be called Weider Öffnen.
再次开始
Open Again.
开始
Allez.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
一
One...
二  三  四
...two, three, four.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
一
One...
你应该事先告诉我她要过来
You should have told me she was coming.
她想亲自感受一下苏西
She wanted to fell Susie for herself.
所以你把她放在
So you put her...
地板下面的
in a storage closet!
储藏间里
Under the floor?
海莲娜·马科斯
Helena Markos?
母亲想要这样
Mother wanted it.
我们不是同意不再用那个头衔了吗
I though we agreed to stop using that title.
如果马科斯真是三母亲之一
If Markos really were one of the Three Mothers
我们就不会陷入这个尴尬局面
we wouldn't be in this situation.
班尼恩小姐的事你应该自己告诉马科斯
You should have told Markos about Miss Bannion yourself.
现在母亲想要她
Now Mother wants her.
我们这么快就又要浪费一个女孩吗
Are we going to waste another girl so quickly?
大家都投过票了
Everyone voted.
我们没有选择你作为领袖
You are not the light we chose to follow.
如果马科斯想要这个女孩  那你就得为她做好准备
If Markos wants this girl, you must prepare her.
她想要吗
And does she?
是的
Yes!
马科斯能活下去
Markos will live.
我们及时找到了这个女孩
We found the girl in time.
我不用着急了
I won't rush again.
这个女孩准备好的时候  我会亲自告诉马科斯
I will tell Markos when the girl is ready.
巴尔福
Miss Balfour!
好了
Alright!
发生什么事了吗
Did something happen?
你跳舞的时候
To you, during it?
没  没有
N-No.
你有没有  有没有...
Did you... did you...
你有没有感觉到什么
Did you feel something there?
什么人
Someone?
或是什么东西
Or just something.
你怎么会这么问
What made you say that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我把你问懵了吗
Am I confusing you?
没有  就是
No, it's, um...
感觉很奇怪  这是...
It's odd. It's the...
这是帕特里夏会说的那种话
It's the sort of thing Patricia would say.
很古怪
It's bizarre.
走吧
Come on.
我们换个衣服  不然索尼娅就自己走了
Let's get changed, or Sonia will leave without us.
我有你能穿的裙子
I've got a dress you can wear.
两个酷女孩
Double caposhi.
苏西
Susie!
Oh, Susie!
我想用老式的方法
I want to bring in a custom from the old ways.
你有什么想法
What do you have in mind?
一个见证人
A witness.
我们新认识的警察朋友中的一个
One of our new friends from the police?
为什么不在窗外漂亮的小东西中挑一个
Why not one of those young things at the window?
我们已经有位见证人了
You're forgetting we already have a witness.
那个把警察叫到我们房子的老男人
The old man who sent us the police in the first place.
他会成为我们的见证人
He will be our winess.
对  不能是这些女孩
Yes. Not one of our girls.
这会让她们发疯的
It would make any of them insane.
没错
I agree.
让苏西看见我们这样也是好事
And it's good for Susie to see us like this.
我们仍属于这个世界
That we're still part of the world.
也许她还感受到了我们的企图
Maybe she even senses what we want of her.
她能感受到很多
She senses a lot.
你能看见她眼睛放光
You can see her eyes shine with it.
我每天晚上都能看到
I see it every night.
就在我把我们的梦托给她的时候
When I send her our dreams.
是真的吗
Is it true?
我知道我是谁
I know who I am!
没事了
It's all right.
It's okay.
她没事吧
Is she all right?
只是做了个噩梦
It's just a nightmare.
马科斯舞团特制
The Markos Company special.
没想到你过这么久才做噩梦
I'm surprised it took this long.
如果她需要安定就告诉我
Hey, let me know if she needs a Valium.
她说得没错  我刚来这里时睡不好觉
She's right. I dreamt of hairballs in toilets
连着三周天天梦到厕所里的头发团
for three weeks before I got a decent night of sleep here.
过去点
Move over.
我只和我的姐姐一起同床睡过
I've only ever slept in bed with my sister.
现在我们就是姐妹了
We're sisters now.
第四幕
索取
在刚刚向媒体发布的声明中
In a statement released to the press moments ago,
劫匪头目马蒂亚尔·马哈茂德
the hijacker's leader Martyrer Mahmud
柏林站[西出口]
要求释放巴德尔  艾思林  莫勒
demands Baader, Ensslin, Moeller
以及其它关押在施达姆斯坦监狱的
and the other RAF prisoners
赤色军团囚犯并乘飞机前往摩加迪沙
be released from Stammheim prison and flown to Mogadishu.
早上好
Good morning.
我能见格洛克纳警官或阿尔布雷希特警官吗
I'd like to talk to Detective Glockner or Detective Albrecht.
姓名
Your name?
约瑟夫·克伦佩雷尔
Klemperer, Josef.
稍等
One moment.
为表明态度
...as proof of their intentions,
劫匪把航班飞行员尤尔根·舒曼的尸体
the hijackers threw down onto the tarmac,
扔到了柏油马路上
the body of the flights pilot Jurgen Schumann.
他已头部中枪身亡
He had been shot in the head.
格洛克纳警官的办公室就在右边
Agent Glockner's office is on the right.
请到那边那边坐下  他们会叫你
Have a seat there and they'll call for you.
恐怖分子嫌疑人  你知道这个女人的名字吗
Terror suspect. Do you know this woman's name?
寻人启事
克伦佩雷尔先生
Herr Klemperer?
请进
Please come inside.
我们看了所有的房间
We were shown every room.
没看到任何值得注意的
We didn't see anything worth remembering.
她们都是专业的演员
They are professional performers.
幻觉是她们的手段
Illusion is their craft.
这不是您该操心的
It's not your place to speculate on that.
你们跟那个叫马科斯的女人谈了吗
Did you speak to the woman called Markos?
帕特里夏总叫她"马科斯母亲"
Patricia referred to her as "Mother Markos."
她有这个女人率领女巫团的幻觉
She had a delusion about this woman leading a coven there.
她有这个幻觉已经好几个月了
She had this delusion for months.
您相信女巫吗  医生
Do you believe in witches, Doctor?
不
No.
但是我相信
But I believe that...
人们可以犯下罪行并将其称之为巫术
people can organize themselves to perpetrate crimes and call it magic.
这个我信
That I can believe.
您知道我们这一周是怎么过来的吗  医生
Do you understand the kind of week we are having, Doctor?
格洛克纳警官
Detective Glockner!
这不是我们第一次见面了
This isn't the first time we've met.
您以前是弗里德瑙的警察
You were on the police force in Friedenau, weren't you?
您帮我找过我的妻子
You helped me to try to locate my wife.
您的妻子也失踪了
Your wife also went missing?
苏联执政前两年
Two years before the Russian charge.
安科·米尔  1943年
Ankle Meire. 1943.
根据记录  您帮我排除了波兰
From the records, you helped me cross off Poland.
我仍然非常感激
I'm still grateful.
一  二  三
And one, and two, and three.
One, and two, and three.
一  二  三
And one, and two, and three.
没关系
That's-that's okay.
你要做跳跃吗
Do you want to do the jumps?
好
Okay.
然后
And...
一  二  三
one, and two, and three.
And one, and two, and three.
不
No.
手肘抬高
Elbows higher.
打断一下
All right, one moment.
苏西  跳跃要放松肌肉
Susie, part of the jump is muscle,
随着你的跳跃会越来越放松
and that will develop as you condition,
但是你好像不喜欢这样
but you seem to have an aversion to them,
我不知道为什么
and I don't quite see why.
你很喜欢被束缚在大地上吗
Are you so happy to be stuck to the earth?
落地前要屈膝
There's a yield before the push,
我觉得你还没有理解透彻
which I don't think you're quite understanding.
卡洛琳  你能来帮我们示范一套吗
Caroline. Could you come and do a series for us, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
轮到你了
And now you.
我现在只想
What I really want is to be on...
好好站在在这地板上
on the floor right now, anyway.
当然了
Well, of course.
那是因为你错将肢体上的不足
That's because you're mistaking physical weakness
当做你的艺术追求
with artistic preference.
还因为你累了
And because you're tired.
现在
At this point,
跳跃是与这个地方对你的拉扯对抗
the jumps are opposing the pull of the structure,
但是
but...
这样做还太早了  你不觉得吗
it's soon for that, don't you think?
地板...才是在承受所有舞者的压力
The floor work is... is keeping the other dancers pushed down.
所以这样
So this...
这样才能回响...
this could echo that...
达到更高的高度
...on-on a slightly higher point of elevation.
如果我现在贴近地面
If I stay close to the ground now
然后再直接起跳
and go straight into the jumps where you have them later,
就能更加达到高度
then that's more to the point.
这种抗拒更加
The resistance is more...
强烈
emphatic.
对吧
Right?
我觉得你可能不知道
I don't know how aware you are
我们四十年来住在这里经历了什么
of what times we lived through here 40 years ago.
不知道这里是由什么建造的
Out of which this piece was made.
我们这么多年来付出了惨重的代价
We learned at great cost through those years
才学会了平衡的重要
the value of the balance of things.
每一支射出的弓箭都能感到地球的拉扯
Every arrow that flies feels the pull of the earth,
但我们还是要向上瞄准
but we must aim upwards.
我们要让你置身空中
We need to get you in the air.
别碰她  别碰她  别碰她  别碰她
Leave her, leave her, leave her, leave her, leave...
卡洛琳  不用害怕
Oh, Caroline. Don't be afraid.
一切都会好的  好吗
Eveything will be alright. Yes?
她狠狠地撞到了头
She hit her head hard.
坦兹
我听到了  我希望...
I heard it. I hope...
小姐
Fraulein?
请等一下
One moment, please.
我...我在找和你们舞团的一名舞者
I am... I'm looking for a dancer from your company.
你要找谁
Who are you looking for?
你是莎拉
You are Sara.
是的
Yes.
有什么需要帮忙的吗
May I help you?
我是帕特里夏的一个朋友
I am a friend from Patricia.
当截止时间一到  劫匪就通知警方
When the deadline arrived, the hijackers informed the police,
他们把航班上所有的免费酒都倒在人质身上
they had poured all the flight's duty-free alcohol over the hostages
扬言放火烧掉他们
and were set to ignite them.
但当他们得知西德政府正在走流程
But when they were told the West German Government
释放施达姆斯坦监狱收押的恐怖分子时
was in the process of releasing the terrorists from Stammheim prison,
他们同意将最后期限延长至午夜之后
they agreed to extend the deadline to after midnight.
我不知道是怎么回事
I don't know what to make of any of this.
我知道她都在做些什么
I know the kind of thing she was involved with,
但我不觉得舞团内
but I can't see how any of this
会发生这种事
could be happening inside the company.
她描述为
Well, she describes...
类似于某种夺权的
something like a revolutionary organization
反抗团体
in a crisis of leadership.
由于马科斯重病
With Markos very ill...
我就住在那里
I live there.
那里还有我的朋友
I have friends there.
我没有发现这种情况
I don't see any evidence of this at all.
没有人来接近过我
No one has ever approached me
据我所知也没有人接近过其他女孩
or any of the other girls, as far as I know.
读读这个
Read this.
这是什么
What is this?
这是帕特里夏的日记
This is Patricia's diary.
马科斯母亲
Mother Markos.
迈因霍夫母亲
Mother Meinhof.
舞蹈排练
The dance rehearsal.
政治活动
Political action.
这两者在帕特里夏的生活中
These two areas in Patricia's life
是同样重要的
were of equal importance.
于是就会发生移情
This is how transference happens,
就会出现幻想
how delusion is made.
幻想  莎拉
Delusion, Sara,
就是道出真相的谎言
is a lie that tells a truth.
这上面说"女巫"
This says "Witches."
也许帕特里夏的幻想是和女巫有关的
Maybe Patricia's fantasies about witches,
她是这样应对其他形式的刺激的
they are her way of processing some other form of intrigue.
舞团是一个家
The company's a family.
大家之间非常友爱
There's a lot of love there.
爱和操控
Love and manipulation--
经常...经常会同时出现
they... they share houses very often.
他们形影相随
They are frequent bedfellows.
抱歉  我看不出来
Sorry, I don't see this.
吃吧
Eat.
只不过
Only...
也许是警察遗漏了些什么
maybe the police, they missed something.
帕特里夏的确提到过
And Patricia, she did spoke of...
那幢大楼有隐藏区域
whole hidden areas of the building.
有些隐藏的房间
Actual rooms that are secret.
无意冒犯
I don't want to be disrespectful--
我不...但你既然问了
I don't-- but you're asking me,
-我就告诉你  -拜托
- and I'm telling you... - Oh, please.
这是个舞团
It's a dance company.
我们不会聊别的事
We're not talking about anything else.
莎拉
Sara.
拜托  你仔细再看看
Please, only look closer.
谢谢你对帕特里夏的关心
Thank you for caring for Patricia,
但我希望你以后不要再来了
but I hope you don't come again.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
莎拉  快点
Sara, hurry up.
我累了  我要用厕所
I'm tired. I need the bathroom.
-晚安  朵儿  -晚安
- Good night, Doll. - Good night.
她还没有回来吗
She hasn't come back yet?
也许她去约会了
Maybe she's seeing somebody.
你经常要面对的问题之一是
Part of the issue always
你无法全方位地看到你自己的肢体
is not being able to see your body in space.
镜子中的一个角度或者拍录的片段远远不够
One angle in one mirror or on film is not enough.
舞动不是无声的
Movement is never mute.
而是一种语言
It is a language.
一套在空气中
It's a series of energetic shapes...
传递的能量形态
...written in the air
就像辞藻对语句的塑造
like words forming sentences.
对诗篇的塑造
Like poems.
对祷词的塑造
Like prayers.
就像咒语
Spells?
当你跳跃起来  重要的不是你跳得多高
When you jump, it's not the height
而是你身下的空间
but the space beneath you that matters.
你向空中的每一跃都要像一见钟情
Every leap into the air must be a coup de foudre.
我不明白
I don't understand.
就像一道电光
A strike of lightning.
爱神之箭
A bolt of love, in fact.
真美
That's beautiful.
舞者绝对不能拥有两样特质
There are two things that dance can never be again:
美丽和欢乐
beautiful and cheerful.
今天  我们要把所有美丽的东西都打倒
Today, we need to break the nose of every beautiful thing.
如果你要做舞者
And if you're going to be a dancer,
你必须要学习法语
you must learn French.
不用担心
Try not to worry.
布兰克正在尝试新方法
Blanc is working on the new approach,
我们怎么知道帕特里夏会变成那样
How could we have known what would happen with Patricia?
我们想做的事在现实中还没做过
What we are attempting hasn't been done in living memory.
我们怎么知道能不能成功
How do we know it will work at all?
如果害得那个女孩没命
If it killed that girl
无论用哪个女孩都会死
it may kill any girl we try.
她说得没错
She is not wrong.
帕特里夏最后不是自愿的
Patricia was unwilling in the end.
布兰克认为那就是原因
Blanc believes that was the reason.
我们不应该强迫
We should not have forced it.
她还没准备好
She did not want to be a vessel.
我们想把自己的力量给她
We wanted to bring her into our power
可她却想把百货商场给炸了
but she wanted to blow up departments stores intead.
那姑娘太蠢了
What a fool, that girl.
当你跳别人创造的舞时
When you dance the dance of another,
你就把你自己想象成创造者
you make yourself in the image of its creator.
你放空你自己
You empty yourself
让她的作品存于你的心中
so that her work can live within you.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
嗯
Yeah.
你现在是舞团的一员
You're in a company now.
你要找准你自己的位置
You have to find your right place.
你要决定
You have to decide--
你想成为舞团的哪一部分
what is it you want to be for this company?
是头
Is it the head?
脊柱
The spine?
性爱
The sex?
心脏
The heart?
手
The hands.
我想成为这个舞团的手
I want to be this company's hands.
更高
Higher.
更高  更高
Higher. Higher.
更高
Higher.
更高  更高
Higher! Higher.
更高
Higher.
更高  更高  更高
Higher, higher, higher.
更高
Higher.
更高  更高
Higher. Higher.
更高  更高  更高
Higher. Higher. Higher.
有时候只需要教我两遍
Sometimes I only need to be told twice.
我们怎么知道没人想把我们也炸了
How do we know no one's planning to blow us up, too?
帕特里夏可能把我们的事情告诉任何人
Patricia might have said anything to anyone about us.
就像那个老头
As she did with the old man.
你说的对
You are right.
我们不能泄气
We cannot despair.
我们还有时间
We have time.
有多少时间
How much time?
如果母亲在布兰克将苏西带下来之前死了
If Mother dies before Blanc can deliver us Susie.
这个舞团就完了
this company is finished.
马科斯会为了我们挺住的
Markos will hold on, for us.
你也见过她了
You've seen her.
她的身体就是一座牢笼
Her body's a prison!
病上加病
Disease is on top of disease
她还能坚持多久
How long she can possibly...
33  34  35  36
37  38  39
40  41
57  58  59
60  61  62  63
65  64  63  62
23  22  21
十  九  八
Ten, nine, eight,
七  六
seven, six.
二  一
Two, one.
我们拦不住她
We couldn't stop her!
她拿刀太快了
She was too fast with knife!
她都凉了
She's cold.
快跟我来
Come with me! Quickly!
帕特里夏写到
Patricia wrote about
"三名母亲"随着时间流逝被人遗忘
"Three Mothers" lost in time,
她们早于基督教而存在
predating all Christian invention.
早于上帝  早于恶魔
Pre-God. Pre-Devil.
黑暗之母  眼泪之母
Mother Tenebrarum, Mother Lachrymarum
和叹息之母
and Mother Suspiriorum.
黑暗  眼泪和叹息
Darkness, Tears and Sighs.
我昨晚看到那些东西
I saw images of that last night.
各种瓷器  非常精美的东西
In porcelain, these very fine things.
看得出来她们很有钱
You can tell they have money.
帕特里夏说过  马科斯
Patricia said that, uh, Markos
是其中一位母亲
claims to be one of the Three.
但是她们之间也有分歧
But there is dissent amongst them.
她写了"马科斯派"和"布兰克派"
She wrote about "Markosites" And "Blancites."
内部的分裂
In-Internal division.
布兰克夫人也与这件事有关吗
Madame Blanc's involved in this?
他们认为她们是女巫吗
Do they believe they're witches?
你可以把你的幻想告诉别人  莎拉
You can give someone your delusion, Sara.
就变成了宗教
That's religion.
德意志帝国也是
That was the Reich.
德意志帝国也有这种特征
The Reich had these things.
军衔
Insignia.
秘密授予仪式
Esoteric ritual.
这些"母亲"很可能是
These "Mothers," Yeah, they could be
对隐喻历史中的主要人物的
code names for founding members
一些代称
with metaphoric histories.
我不知道
I don't know.
但我知道你正在和一群危险的人住在一起
But I do know you are living with dangerous people.
帕特里夏可能还...
Patricia could still be in...
在那里
...in there.
她们可能把她关了起来
They could be holding her.
关在楼里
In the building.
最近出了那么多事  我觉得当局
Well, I cannot promise that the authorities
应该不会回来搜查
will come back to, uh, inspect a cabinet
一个装满瓷器的柜子
full of porcelain after all that has happened.
但我们可以努力试试
But we can try.
同时  你得照顾好你自己
And in the meantime, you must, uh, take care of yourself.
也许你应该离开
Perhaps you should leave.
你有什么可去的地方吗
You have somewhere you can go?
我会想办法的
I'll figure it out.
我觉得你应该把这放回去
And I think you should put this back.
或者还是把这留在这里吧
Or better still, you leave it here.
最好别让她们知道你偷拿了
Not good for them to know that you have it.
格非特  我来弄
Griffith, I will take it.
你们中有人生病了吗
Is anyone among you sick?
让他联系教堂的长老
Let him call for the elders of the church;
让他们为他祈祷
and let them pray over him,
以上帝之名用圣油涂抹他的身体
anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord.
出于信心的祈祷  要救那病人
And the prayer of faith shall save him that is sick,
主必叫他起来
and the Lord shall raise him up;
他若犯了罪
and if he has committed sins...
我的女儿
My daughter.
也必蒙赦免
...they shall be forgiven him.
我最小的女儿
My last one.
她就是我的罪
She's my sin.
她是我对世界的玷污
She's what I smeared on the world.
最开始是最重要的  你记得吗
First of all it's very important, do you remember this?
你要用你的中心
You must use your center.
必须要创造出空间
and you must create a space.
我现在明白了
Now I understand.
等等  等等
Wait, wait.
好了
Alright.
悬停  在空中悬停
Suspended, suspended in the air.
记得创造空间
Remember to create space.
我明白了
Yes, I understand.
你和她们达成了某种协议
You're making some kind of deal with them.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你怎么知道她们要你付出什么做回报
How can you know what they're going to ask you in return?
莎拉  不管你是怎么想的
Sara, whatever you have in your mind,
一切都很正常
nothing is wrong.
你只是还没有尝到后果
You just haven't seen the bill yet.
一切都很正常
Nothing's wrong.
德国联邦警察特种兵
Special forces of the German Federal Police
在夜晚突袭了汉莎航空181航班
stromed Lufthansa 181 in the night
击毙了四名劫匪
and killed three of the four hijackers
终结了航班乘客五天来的恐惧
ending five days of terror for the passenger of the flight.
早晨  高度警戒的
In the morning, in the high-security wing
斯图加特施达姆斯坦监狱里
of the Stuutgart-Stammheim prison,
五名RAF集团犯人中
three of the five RAF prisoners were discovered dead
有三人听闻
in an apparent suicide pact
摩加迪沙的消息后自杀
made upon hearing of the news from Mogadishu.
抗议者在德国周围聚集
Protesters are congregating around the Germany
说犯人其实是被刺杀的
chanting that the prisoners were instead assassinated.
联邦警察局局长霍斯特·赫罗尔德宣称
Federal Police President Horst Herold, went so far as to declare...
"巴德尔-迈因霍夫时代终结了"
"The Baader-Meinhof era is done."
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
你不用担心被刷得那么白  苏西
You don't be so afraid about the white, Susie.
后排的观众也得看到你
They need to see you from the very back row.
莎拉在哪里
Where is Sara?
她今天早上很早就来了
She came early in the morning,
化好妆就走了
did her makeup and left.
晚上好  欢迎
Good evening, welcome.
第一次来  对吗
First time here, isn't it?
请进
Please, come.
好的  谢谢  祝您愉快
Yes, thank you. Have fun.
直走
Straight ahead.
第五幕
在母亲的房子
[地面皆为黑暗]
姑娘们
Girls!
四分钟
Vier minuten!
Four minutes!
四分钟
Vier minuten!
快  快
Tak, tak.
这是真的吗
Is it true?
莎拉
Sara.
帕特里夏
Patricia.
帕特里夏  帕特里夏
Patricia. Patricia.
-我就知道  -他们会杀了他
- I knew it. - They'll kill him.
我很抱歉我这么久才来
I'm sorry it took me so long.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
他们对你做了什么
What did they do to you?
我每天都在这里醒来
I wake up here every day.
一切都结束了  我救你出去
It's all over now. I'll get you out.
楼上的表演要开始了
The performance is starting upstairs.
所有人都不会注意到的
Everyone will be looking the other way.
起来  起来
Get up. Get up.
帕特里夏
Patricia!
-帕特里夏  起来  -我在努力
- Patricia, get up. - I'm trying.
起来
Get up.
帮我出来
Get it off of me!
莎拉
Sara!
马科斯  马科斯  马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos! Markos! Markos!
晚上好
Good evening!
这段舞创造于1948年
We created this piece in 1948.
马尔凯塔
Marketa.
莎拉在哪里
Where is Sara?
莎拉
Sara?
我不知道
I don't know.
-她在楼上吗  -没有  我找过了
- Is she upstairs? - No. I looked.
像她还在一样照常跳
Just dance as if she's with you.
莎拉
Sara!
这是我们最后一次表演这个舞
This is the last time we are performing it.
由马科斯舞团演绎
The Markos Dance Company presents.
请观赏
Volk!
上
Go!
不
No.
亲爱的
My darling..
-不  -莎拉  不要动
- No. - Sara, lie still.
-不  莎拉
- No! - Sara.
不要  不要
Please. Please...
不  不
No! No!
这姑娘准备好了  布兰克
The girl is ready, Blanc.
到时候了
It's time.
请坐下
Please, remain seated!
请保持冷静
Stay calm and seated!
莎拉
Sara!
好了
Good.
好了  这样好了
Good. That's good.
抱歉我当时失态了
I'm sorry I went off book.
以后不得再发生这种事
This can't happen again.
你才刚刚开始理解  苏西
You're only just starting to understand, Susie.
我们把莎拉带回到楼上
We brought Sara back upstairs
只是为了能圆满完成演出
to try to complete the performance in time,
而你却搞砸了
but then you derailed it.
我伤害了那些人吗
Did I hurt those people?
这次没有
Not this time.
他们看到了一支舞
They saw a dance.
那就够了
That's all.
一切都一团糟  是吗
It's all a mess, isn't it?
外面的世界
The one out there.
里面的世界
The one in here.
将要来临的世界
The one that's coming.
为什么大家
Why is everyone
都愿意认为最糟糕的已经过去呢
so ready to think the worst is over?
我可以向你解释一切
I could explain everything to you.
但我觉得我不该这么做
I think it would be wrong, though.
你不想让我做出选择
You don't want to make me choose.
因为你爱我
Because you love me.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
今晚不会有梦
No more dreams tonight.
绝对不会
I'll make sure of it.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
第六幕
叹息
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
今晚
Tonight.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
一定要在今晚进行
It must happen tonight.
医生
Herr Doktor.
医生  汤好了
But Doctor, the soup is ready!
你们今天吃喝随便
You can eat and drink all that you want!
谁在那里
Hello?
约瑟夫
Josef?
安科
Anke?
卡萝尔把我们的事情告诉他们了
Karol told them about us.
我当时只有几分钟时间
I had only a few minutes to get out.
我回到家  但是我的证件不见了
I got the apartment, but my papers were'n't anywhere.
我就徒步走到特普利斯
Then I traveled by foot to Teplice.
我本打算求米雷克家收留我
where I planned to ask Mireks family to take me in.
但是我在边境被抓了
But I was caught at the border
被带到了特莱西恩施塔特集中营
and taken to Theresienstadt camp
没人相信我是在加尔茨出生的
No one believed me that I was born in Gartz.
解放之后我就去了苏黎世
After the liberation I made my way Zurich
然后去了布里斯托尔
and then to Bristol.
我在那
I've made
有了新的生活
a new life there.
幸福的生活
A lovely life.
我听说
I was told
你在入侵时期遇害了
you'd died in the invasion.
普伦特森林站
坦兹
看他把这个弄得多脏
Look how dirty he made it!
可怜可怜我
Have a pity!
凭什么可怜你
What reason is there to pity you?
批捕之前你有那么多年的时间
You had years to get your wife out of Berlin
把你妻子送出柏林
before the arrests began.
当女人跟你说实话的时候
When women tell you the truth
你不可怜她们
You don't pity them.
你却说她们有幻觉
You tell them they have delusions!
我是无辜的
I am innocent!
我都记得
I remember!
我是无辜的
I am innocent!
柏林有罪人吗
Are there guilty men in Berlin?
到处都是
Everywhere!
但我不是
But I am not one of them!
我准备好了  夫人
I'm ready, Madame.
你看上去很害怕
You look afraid.
她是为你而害怕
She's afraid for you.
你将不会再
There will be nothing of you
存在
left inside.
只留下我的空间
Only space for me.
我就是为此而来的
I came here for this.
你们都等了够久了
You've all waited long enough.
要开始了
It is happening.
It is happening!
你是自愿来的吗
Do you come here willingly?
你不能心怀一丝疑虑  苏西
You must have no doubts, Susie.
如果还有疑虑  我可以带你回去
If you do, I can take you back.
我可以让你忘掉这一切
I can take all of this from your head.
你可以忘掉一切
You can forget everything.
我想要非常纯净
I want this to be pure.
我们都知道你想要什么
We all know what you want.
这不是什么浮华
This isn't vanity.
这不是
This isn't...
艺术
art!
有点不对劲
There is something wrong here.
你感觉不到吗
Can you not feel it?
不对劲
This is not right.
我们得停下来
We have to stop this now.
我们已经
We have been on
分裂了
two sides of this
太久
for too long now.
马科斯  马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos! Markos!
马科斯  马科斯  马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos! Markos! Markos!
马科斯  马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos! Markos!
马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos!
马科斯  马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos! Markos!
马科斯  马科斯
Markos! Markos!
如果你接受我
If you accept me,
那你必须干掉烦扰你的那个女人
you must put down the woman who bore you.
想想那个假的母亲
Think of that false mother now.
拒绝她
Reject her.
放逐她
Expel her.
你唯一需要的母亲在这里
You have the only mother you need here.
其他母亲都死
Death to any other mother.
说出来
Say it.
其他母亲都死
Death to any other mother.
你是谁
Who are you?
你受谁涂油
For whom were you anointed?
三个母亲中的哪一位
Which of the Three Mothers?
叹...
Mother...
叹息之母
Mother Suspiriorum.
我就是她
I am she.
字幕
Markos.
马科斯
Markos!
Markos.
其他母亲都死
Death to any other mother.
马科斯
Markos.
Markos!
马科斯
我是母亲
I am the Mother.
你想要什么
What do you ask?
死
To die.
母亲
Mother.
母亲  我们好累
Mother, we're so tired.
你想要什么
What do you ask?
死
To die.
我想要死
I want to die.
可爱的女孩
Sweet girl.
你想要什么
What do you ask?
死
Die.
没错
Yes.
跳吧  跳吧
Dance. Dance.
继续跳吧
Keep dancing.
真美
It's beautiful.
小心台阶
Watch your step.
下雪了
It's been snowing.
一切都很美
Everything is pretty.
小心  慢点
And again, slowly.
嗯
Yeah. Okay.
很好  很好
Good. Good.
晚上好  晚安
Good evening, good night,
身盖玫瑰
with roses covered
丁香环绕
with cloves adorned
进入梦乡
slip under the covers.
明天早晨  如果上帝愿意
Tomorrow morning, if God wills
一会再次醒来
you will wake once again.
尾声
切好的梨
天啊  这一晚真是够受的
My God, what a night.
我绝对是喝太多了
I definitely drank too much wine.
坦纳和巴尔福的歌呢
And what about the song of Tanner and Balfour?
太棒了
It was fantastic!
-早上好  -早上好
- Bonjour. - Bonjour.
我很喜欢
Yes, I adore it!
-早上好  -早上好
- Guten Morgen. - Morning.
早上好
Good morning.
女孩们  听好了
Girls, I need you to listen.
我有个坏消息  希望你们听到时要坚强
I have such a sad news and I want you to be brave when you hear it.
布兰克夫人离开了舞团
Madame Blanc has left the company.
雅利安报
这样不行  医生
This is not the way to do it, Doctor.
我差点报警
I nearly called the police myself.
你不舒服  我知道
You haven't been well, I know.
你是谁  你怎么进来的
Who are you? How did you get in here?
到外面等
Wait outside.
我对我女儿们对你所做之事而感到懊悔
I regret what my daughters did to you.
我当时没有阻止她们
I wasn't in a position to prevent it.
我认为你应该知道真相
I believe you deserve to know the truth.
你妻子当时是想往南
Your wife did try to make it south
逃往特普利斯
to Teplice.
她在格拉苏蒂外的树林里
She was apprehended by border guards
被边境警察抓住
in the woods just outside of Glashuütte.
带到了特莱西恩施塔特集中营
She was then taken to Theresienstadt camp.
她在那儿过了20天
She lived there for 20 days.
在1943年11月11日
On the 11th of November, 1943,
营地指挥官  一个叫伯格的人
the commandant of the camp, a man named Burger...
命令所有四万名囚犯
...ordered all 40,000 detained there
站在冷风中进行人数清点
stand outside in the cold for a census.
过去了一个又一个小时
Hours and hours passed.
有几百人被冻死
Some hundreds died of exposure.
你妻子在死时和另外两名女人在一起
Your wife had two women with her as she died.
她和她们成为了朋友
Women she had befriended,
让她感觉没有那么孤单
who made her feel that she was not alone.
她最后的念头
Her final thoughts...
是一次生日
were of a birthday
你带她去一场音乐会  给了她一个惊喜
when you took her to a concert as a surprise.
肖邦和勃拉姆斯
Chopin and Brahms.
这是你第一次握住她的手
It was the first time you held her hand.
她死时很冷
She was cold when she died.
但她不害怕
But she wasn't afraid.
她只想着你
She was thinking only of you.
安科·梅尔
Of Anke Meier...
帕特里夏·亨格尔
...of Patricia Hingle...
莎拉·希姆斯
...of Sara Simms...
苏珊娜·班尼恩
...of Susanna Bannion,
你所有未能解救的女人
of all the women of your undoing...
所有记忆都会消失
...every memory will vanish.
都会在阳光下融化
They will melt away in the sun
然后消失
and be gone.
我们需要罪恶
We need guilt,
医生
Doctor.
还有羞耻
And shame.
但不是你的
But not yours.
医生
Herr Doktor.
你是谁
Who are you?
西萨姆小姐
Miss Sesame!
-是吗  -是的
-Ja? -Ja.